Jaden Chew Wei Jie

Mobile: +6011-26943868 Email: wjchew95@gmail.com

Profile Summary



I am a fully ACA Qualified ICAEW Chartered Accountant with experience across both financial and non-financial services clients in the audit sector. I have previously worked as a Senior Assurance Associate at PwC UK, where I was responsible for leading teams towards the completion of several audit engagements within tight deadlines. I most recently worked as a Senior Finance Manager at Proton Commerce, a 50:50 joint venture company set up between CIMB and Proton. Currently pursuing software development full-time through Sigma School, with the goal of transitioning into the tech industry. Open to both internship and entry level software developer positions.

Employment History

Proton Commerce Sdn Bhd

June 2020 – October 2023

Senior Finance Manager

- Oversee the daily operations of the accounts and finance department
- Responsible for the month-end closing process and submission of the company's monthly Profit & Loss and Balance Sheet to CIMB and Proton
- Present the monthly finance report to internal stakeholders
- Prepare the quarterly finance report presentation and papers for the Board of Directors meeting
- Perform cash flow forecast and ensure the efficient allocation of spare funds through short-term fixed deposit placement
- Review accounting entries, monthly tax computation and maintenance of the financial and accounting records
- Review and ensure payments for taxes, staff claims, incentives and vendors are done on a timely basis
- Provide guidance and assistance to finance executives on financial and accounting matters
- Liaise with auditors to ensure that the annual audit of the company's accounts is completed within the deadline given by Proton Group
- Liaise with tax agents on the company's annual tax payable and revision of tax estimates. Successfully reduced YA2020 tax penalty to nil after ensuring that all tax-deductible expenses were taken into account\

Schlumberger Business Support Hub Sdn Bhd

March 2020 – May 2020

Statutory Accounting Analyst (Contract)

- Maintained general ledger accounts and related processes for the production of financial statements and reports
- Ensured that the accounting entries are in compliance with the statutory reporting requirement
- Prepared supporting schedules for tax authority audits and statutory audits

Senior Assurance Associate

- Led teams to complete the audits of various engagements within tight deadlines
- Ensured that the accounts being audited complies with the relevant accounting standards and financial reporting requirements
- Carried out financial analysis over the accounts such as variance and trend analysis to identify any potential fraud or irregularities in the companies' operations
- Developed effective working relationships with clients to ensure that issues are resolved quickly and that deliverables are provided on time
- Coached and guided junior team members with their work
- Coordinated with firm specialist teams based remotely in India and Poland to complete specific parts of the audit
- Identified key issues encountered during each engagement and discussed practical solutions to resolve them efficiently with the team

PwC Manchester (UK)

January 2016 - March 2018

Assurance Associate

- Completed 3 work placements, with each placement during the firm's busiest months of the year (Jan Mar 2016; Jan Mar 2017; Nov Mar 2018)
- Took ownership of my assigned sections of the audit and ensured that they were completed to the expectations of my managers and seniors
- Discussed issues encountered and progress updates with seniors and managers on a regular basis
- Proactively liaised with client contacts to resolve audit queries both on site and remotely when necessary. For example, on one of my audits, I organised virtual WebEx meetings with client contacts in London and New York to walkthrough the interest payments process and calculations

Professional Certifications

ICAEW (Institute of Chartered Accountants in England and Wales)

Associate Member, ACA Qualified

MIA (Malaysian Institute of Accountants)

Chartered Accountant

Education

Newcastle University (UK)

September 2014 - June 2018

BA (Hons) Business, Accounting and Finance

Taylors College Subang Jaya

January 2013 – June 2014

Cambridge A-Levels (Achieved 4A* in all subjects)

SMK USJ 4

January 2008 – December 2012

SPM (Achieved 8A+, 1A, 1A-)

Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Microsoft Office